Alexander Vasilenko

Full stack web developer & Information systems analyst



About me

I am Alexander. A Full stack web developer, and an Information systems analyst looking for a challenging position to develop professionally and grow personally.

Eager to learn new skills, work with new technologies, take on extra responsibilities, set personal and professional goals, and surpass them.

Autodidact, motivated, disciplined, and devoted with strong organizational skills and great capabilities in interpersonal relationships. Able to take initiative and lead when needed.

A Confident public speaker with solid presentation skills and great expressiveness.

A great team player who brings 2 years of experience in full-stack web development in addition to 2 years of experience in system analysis and project management to the table.

Contact Information



alexandervjr1@gmail.com Klauzner 8 Ra'anana Israel Israeli



050-814-5431 https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexand er-vasilenko99/

Experience

2022- Present

Full Stack Developer

Self-Employed

Responsible for designing, developing, and maintaining full-stack web applications.

- Built tens of beautiful web applications from scratch, maintained and managed existing web applications generating clients a total revenue of thousands of dollars.
- Problem-solving major operational issues by reverse-engineering workflows saving clients a potential revenue of tens of thousands of dollars
- Provided general back-office management and tech support.

2021- 2023

Information Systems Analyst

IDF - Unit 61(Meitav)

Responsible for system analysis, characterization, correct

- implementation, product testing, and large-scale project management.
 Characterized and tested the implementation of the Socio-Economic Index of Local Authorities by the *Israel Central Bureau of Statistics* into the IDF's SAP. The index is now being used by over 500 soldiers and officers affecting all IDF candidates' procedures of assignment before and after their enlistment.
- Was responsible for examining, comparing, and vetoing various low-code solutions of well-known companies before the adaptation and implementation of the most relevant by the unit and its software development team.
- Was responsible for being the connecting factor between the IDF and a translation company for adding the Amharic language to the IDF's Dapar tests in order to help improve the precision of recruitees' military role assignments.
- Participated in meetings, answered calls, responded to emails, made presentations, and spoke with clients and suppliers on a daily basis.

2021- 2021

Student Pilot

IDF - Air Force

- Successfully handled complicated situations under difficult circumstances by quick decision-making in the air, in class, and in the field.
- Accumulated 10 flight hours.

Finished military service with 2 excelense awards.

Education

2023 - 2024, Tel Aviv Israel

Full Stack Developer

John Bryce Academy

Graduated with honors in February 2024. Grade: 100

2015 - 2018, Ra'anana Israel

High School Diploma

Ostrovsky High School

Studied in *Nachshon* class for leadership and excellence. Majored in computer science, planning and programming systems, math, physics, and English.

Skills

HTML CSS JavaScript

- TypeScript
- React
- Redux
- AngularREST API
- -- 1
- Node.jsExpress
- OOP
- Bootstrap
- Git/Github
- SQL
- MySQL
- Microservices
- Docker
- Cloud
- Socket.io
- jQuery
- MongoDB
- RegEx
- SDLC
- SAP
- Smoove

Languages

Hebrew native

English

advanced

Russian intermediate